BASIM ALMANSOOR

Villa 3 Road 7317 Block 473 Abu-Saiba, Bahrain

(+973) 3446190 CPR No. 861203070

PROFILE

A self-motivated and ambitious team leader with over 10 years of experience in customer service and insurance. Throughout my professional career, I have taken different progressive roles gaining several transferrable and managerial skills. I was able to move from junior roles to leading teams of over 6 people taking up more responsibilities and tasks. I am IT-literate with an emphasis on teamwork and proven experience in customer-facing roles. I am adaptable and able to work in a fast-paced environment. My experience is supported with professional courses and certifications that has enabled me to grow and learn. I am seeking a position that utilizes my skills and experience in a growing organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Royal Bahrain Hospital (RBH)

Manama, BH

Mar 2016 - Present

bassim.almansoor@gmail.com DOB: 31st December 1986

Insurance Team Leader

- Overseeing a team of 12 people of various levels of responsibilities from junior officers to senior officers.
- Responsible for organizing over 20 clinics' patients' schedules.
- Record employee attendance, coordinate overtime schedule and produce daily reports.
- Audit patients bills for insurance payments.
- Review patients' policy details against table of benefits.
- Manage an average of 150 insurance approvals per day.
- Produce duty roster reports for Riffa and Manama branches.
- Resolve an average of 20 patient complaints per month.

Royal Bahrain Hospital (RBH)

Manama, BH

Mar 2014 - Mar 2016

- Insurance Officer Booked and organized appointments for more than 300 patients per week.
 - Responsible for admitting patients to the 15 wards in the hospital.
 - Handled the collection of deductibles and advanced payments.
 - Followed up with patients for payments approval or rejection.
 - Generated reports for consultations and lab reports with patients' invoice.

International Hospital of Bahrain (IBH)

Jidhafs, BH

Administration Receptionist and Insurance Officer

Oct 2012- Feb 2014

- Organized appointments for an average of 100 patients per week.
- Produced daily staff reports for a team of 4 employees to the departments' supervisors.
- Supervised and maintained daily cash receivables.
- Finalized patients' pricing, invoices and room packages.

Bahrain Specialist Hospital (BSH)

Juffair, BH

Senior Receptionist

Feb 2011- Aug 2012

- Booked and organized appointments for 200-300 patients per week.
- Wrote daily reports to the supervisors about blocking clinics and staff delays.
- Followed up with patients about their appointments and dealt with changing schedules.

Nest Computer Systems

Salmabad, BH

Computer Technician

Jul 2009- Sep 2009

- Installed security systems at homes and companies which included camera surveillance systems and finger print
- Troubleshoot networks and computer problems

Citi Bank Receptionist - Operation & Technology Department

Seef District, BH Jul 2008- Aug 2008

Dealt with customer's enquiries and problems.

Updated customer information on the department's database.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS AND COURSES

- Insurance Auditing from Berlitz June 2018
- Personality Development from Impact Institute December 2015
- Handling Difficult People from Impact Institute December 2015
- The Art of Professional Business Writing from Bright Future Training Centr December 2015
- Customer Excellence from Berlitz July 2015
- Patient's Rights and Responsibilities April 2013
- Telephone Etiquette from International Hospital of Bahrain Jan 2013
- Customer Care from Industrial Petroleum Training Services November 2012
- Professional Telephone Behavior from Bird Institute- May 2012
- Settlement of Commercial and Labor Disputes from Design-Tech Training Centre November 2011
- Prevention & Control of Infection (PCI) from Bahrain Specialist Hospital-June 2011
- Essential Skills to Improve Productivity & Performance from Ait Center February 2011
- Network+ from Bahrain Training Institute July 2009
- IT Essentials 2- PC hardware and Software October 2008
- IT Essentials 2 Cisco Certificate from Bahrain Training Institute- July 2008
- IT Essentials 1 Cisco Certificate from Bahrain Training Institute- July 2007

EDUCATION

Bahrain Training Institute (BTI)

BTEC National Diploma in Computer Networks and ICT

Isa Town, BH July 2009

- Academic: GPA of 2.75
- Extracurricular activities: Member of the BTI football team.

Bahrain Training Institute

BTEC First Diploma in Computer Studies

Isa Town, BH

Jul 2007

- Academic: GPA of 2.62
- The demands of the course have developed several skills such as self-directed learning, problem solving skills as well as time management.

Ahmed Alomran Secondary School Tawjeehi certificate in commercial stream

Manama, BH

Jun 2004

ADDITIONAL

- Languages: Arabic (Native), English (Fluent)
- Computer Skills
 - o Proficient in using Microsoft Office programs (Excel, Word, PowerPoint)
 - Other software skills include Adobe Photoshop, Visual Basic, Proghramming with C++, HTML code.
- Football
 - Active player with Bahrain Royal Hospital football team taking part in Bahrain's intra-mural companies football tournaments and competitions.
 - o Played with Abu-Saiba football team competing in national and local tournaments.
- References are available upon request